Guide to the Stephan Loewentheil photograph collection, 1822-1979.
Loewentheil, Stephan photograph collection
- Series V. Mathew Brady and the Civil War
  - Brady and Unattributed Daguerreotypes, and Brady Cases Without Images
    - Young woman, Bust portrait, seated; D-50, 1840s (Box V-3)
    - Very Young Boy, seated; D-51, Seated portrait (Box V-3)
    - Man with Cloak (Box V-3)
    - Francis P. Howe; D-53, D-54, D-55 & D-56 (Box V-3)
    - Teenage Boy (Box V-3)
    - Unidentified Brady (Box V-3)
    - Stern Looking Woman, 1848-1852 (Box V-6)
      Hand-colored daguerreotype in wooden frame
    - 4 1/6 plate single booked daguerreotype leather cases (empty)
      C-1 to C-4
  - Brady Ambrotypes and Tintypes
    - Young Man, Half-length Portrait; A-2 (Box V-4)
    - Woman, Half-length Portrait; A-3 (Box V-4)
      TINTYPE mistakenly labeled as an ambrotype, in Brady case.
    - Hand-tinted Mustachioed Man, Half-length Portrait; A-5 (Box V-4)
    - Benjamin Richards, Sr., Three-quarter Length Portrait; A-7 (Box V-4)
      With CDV portrait of Benjamin Richards by Thomas Faris
    - Mrs. Benjamin Richards, Three-quarter Length Portrait; A-8 (Box V-4)
    - Little Girl, Full-length Seated Portrait; A-9 (Box V-4)
      Unidentified photographer in Brady case.
    - Woman; A-10 (Box V-4)
    - Young Woman, Vignette Portrait; A-12 (Box V-4)
    - Young Woman, Three-quarter Length Seated Portrait; A-13 (Box V-4)
    - Man, Three-quarter Length Seated Portrait; A-14 (Box V-4)
    - Man, Half-length Portrait, A-15 (Box V-4)
    - Young Girl with Purse, Full Length Portrait; A-18 (Box V-4)
    - Young Boy in Black Cape with Ruffled Collar, Full-length Portrait; A-20 (Box V-4)
    - Teen Boy, Half-length Portrait; A-26 (Box V-4)
    - Woman (Box V-4)
      Double ambrotype
    - Woman, Head and Shoulders Portrait; A-1 (Box V-5)
    - Photograph of a Crayon Portrait of a Woman; A-6 (Box V-5)
    - Family Portrait of Seven Women; A-11 (Box V-5)
      Double sided.
    - Francis P. Howe; A-24 (Box V-5)
    - Older Man, Half-length Portrait; A-27 (Box V-5)
    - Woman in Spanish Dress; A-25, 1854 (Box V-7)
      Whole plate ambrotype with brass mat, A-25
  - Other Brady Photographs
    - Jonathan Wainwright, Bishop of New York, 1854 (Box V-16, Folder 1)
      With "Lines written on the death of Bishop Wainwright"
    - Seated Gentleman, Undated (Box V-16, Folder 1)
    - John James Audubon, Undated (Box V-16, Folder 1)
    - Two Prints of West Point Grounds, Undated (Box V-16, Folder 2)
    - Severn Teackle Wallis, late 1850s (Box V-17)
    - William Alfred Buckingham, Undated (Box V-17)
    - Unidentified Woman, Undated (Box V-17, Folder 2)
    - Architectural Drawing, Undated (Box V-17, Folder 2)
    - Brady Cabinet Cards (Binder), Undated (Box V-19)
  - Engravings and Lithographs After Photographs
    These engravings mainly appeared in Harper's Weekly and Leslie's Illustrated News
    - Engravings and Lithographs After Brady Photographs
      - Illustrations of "The Embarkation of the Fire Zouaves on Board the Baltic," Edwin M. Stanton, and Abraham Lincoln (memorial portrait), 1861-1866 (Box V-10, Folder 1)
      - Covers of the Illustrated News, 1853-03-19-1853-11-12 (Box V-10, Folder 2)
        March 19, 1853 and November 12, 1853
      - Covers of Harper's Weekly, 1858-02-06-1858-02-27 (Box V-10, Folder 2)
        February 6, 13, 27
      - Covers of Harper's Weekly, 1858-03-06-1858-04-24 (Box V-10, Folder 3)
        March 6, 20, 27 and April 10, 24
      - Covers of Harper's Weekly, 1858-05-01-1858-06-26 (Box V-10, Folder 4)
        May 1, 8, 15, 22 and June 26
      - Covers of Harper's Weekly, 1858-07-10-1858-08-21 (Box V-10, Folder 5)
        July 10, 17, 24; August 21
      - Covers of Harper's Weekly, 1858-09-25-18-1858-11-06 (Box V-10, Folder 6)
        September 4, 25, October 16, November 6, 1858
      - Covers and pages of Harper's Weekly, 1860-05-26-1861-11-23 (Box V-10, Folder 7)
        February 18, 1860, May 26 and November 3, 1860; April 27, July 13 and November 23, 1861
      - Covers and pages of Harper's Weekly, 1863-02-21-1865-12-23 (Box V-10, Folder 8)
        February 21 and September 12, 1863; March 19 and October 8, 1864; September 2 and December 23, 1865
      - Covers and pages of Harper's Weekly and Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1866-01-13-1877-05-05 (Box V-10, Folder 9)
        January 13, February 17, 1866; April 18, July 25, 1868; August 26, 1871; April 20, 1872; May 5, 1877
      - Covers and pages of Harper's Weekly and Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1866-01-13-1877-05-05 (Box V-10, Folder 9)
      - Issues of Harper's Weekly, 1861-03-16-1862-12-06 (Box V-10, Folder 10)
        March 16, 1861; August 9 and December 6, 1862
      - Lincoln, His Cabinet, and Civil War Officers - Engravings after Brady Photographs, Circa 1860s, undated (Box V-18)
    - Engravings and Lithographs After Photographs by other photographers
      Engravings from illustrated magazines by Photographers other than Brady.
      - Covers of Harper's Weekly, 1865-05-06-1866-02-10 (Box V-10, Folder 13)
        May 6 and May 13, 1865; February 10, 1866
  - Portraits of Brady and Brady Studio Receipts
    - "The Electoral Commission", Undated (Box V-13)
    - Brady Gallery Receipt for One Photograph, 1857 (Box V-16, Folder 3)
    - Civil War Era Receipt for 12 Cartes de Visite, 1862 (Box V-16, Folder 3)
    - Brady in the Field in Gettysburg, July 15, 1863 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Cabinet card with image of Brady, Circa 1870s (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Photographed by Sarony.
    - Stereo views of Brady's Studio (Box V-22)
    - Stereo views with Brady in the Image (Box V-22)
  - Civil War Photographs
    - Framed Portrait of General Grant (Box V-8)
    - Civil War Stereo Views (Box V-9, 19, 22, 24)
    - War views, June; Brady, Mathew B. (Box V-9)
      2388, 2369, 4002, 3459, 3420, 3417, 3387, 3658, 3503, 3465, 3461, 3354, 3344, 3199, 3192, 3059, 3049, 3120, 3120, 2669, 2500, 2496, 2495, 2482, 2479, 2463, 2447, 2426, 2411, 2394, 2387, 2385, 2384, 2379, 2361, 2359, 2358, 2356, 2351, 2333, 2332, 2331, 2330, 232, 2317, 2316, 2313, 2312, 2310, 2424, 2434, 3635, 3627, 2506, 816, 3426, 2493, 2433
      United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Photography
      Stereographs
    - Brady's "Incidents of the War", 1861
      - Camp McDowell, 8th Regiment N.Y.S.T., Arlington Heights, Virginia, 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - Drummer Boys, 8th Regiment N.Y.S.T., Arlington Heights, Virginia (Camp McDowell), 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - New York 71st Infantry at the Washington Navy Yard, 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - 2nd Rhode Island Infantry with Colonel Frank Wheaton at Camp Brightwood, Washington D.C., 1862; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - Signal Camp of Instruction, Near Georgetown, Washington D.C., 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - Signal Camp of Instruction, Near Georgetown, Washington D.C., 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - Signal Camp of Instruction, Washington D.C., 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - Camp 1st Connecticut Artillery, Colonel R.O. Tyler, Fort Richardson, Virginia, 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
        Interior of the defense fort in wintertime.
      - Camp 1st Connecticut Artillery, Colonel R.O. Tyler, Fort Richardson, Virginia, 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
        Interior views of soldiers drilling.
      - General McDowell and Staff, Arlington Heights, Virginia, 1861; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - Camp 55th New York Volunteers at Fort Gains near Tenalytown, Washington D.C., 1862; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - 17th Regiment New York Volunteers, Company F, Colonel H.S. Lansing, Butterfield's Brigade, Fitz Porters Division, Halls Hill, Virginia, 1862; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - 96th Pennsylvania Camp Northumberland, Fairfax, Virginia, March 1, 1862; 41.8 x 59 cm (Box V-11)
      - 8th New York Militia at Camp McDowell, Circa July 1861; 36.8 x 26.7 cm (Box V-14)
      - Loose text pages from "Brady's Incident’s of War" (Box V-17, Folder 1)
    - Brady's "Views in the Navy Ordinance Yard", 1866 (Box V-12)
      6 matted prints
    - "Brady Photographs" and other photographs by Alexander Gardner
      - Headquarters, General Graham's Brigade, Camp 31st Regiment Pennsylvania Volunteers, 1861 (Box V-11)
        From "Brady's Incident’s of War"
      - Colonel Michael Corcoran and Officers, 69th New York in Fort Corcoran, 1861 (Box V-11)
      - 3rd Connecticut Regiment (Camp Douglas), 1861 (Box V-11)
      - Camp at Cumberland Landing, on the Pamunkey River, 1862 (Box V-13)
        Panorama consisting of 5 prints.
      - Company D, 6th Vermont at Camp Griffin, 1861; 24.1 x 35.6 cm (Box V-14)
      - Sixth Vermont Infantry, Camp Griffin, Circa 1861; 24.1 x 35.6 cm (Box V-14)
      - Major General E.V. Sumner and Staff, Warrenton, November 13, 1862 (Box V-15)
      - General Marcy and Friends, Headquarters Army of Potomac, Near Antietam, October 3, 1862 (Box V-15)
      - Antietam Bridge, on the Sharpsburgh and Boonsboro' Turnpike, September 17, 1862 (Box V-15)
      - The Burnside Bridge Over the Antietam, September 17, 1862 (Box V-15)
      - Pontoon Bridge Across the Potomac, Berlin, November 1, 1862 (Box V-15)
      - Wagon Pulled by Mules Fording a Stream, Circa 1865 (Box V-15)
      - Military Bridge Across the Chickahominy, Virginia, 1864 (Box V-15)
        Photographed by D.B. Woodbury and published by Alexander Gardner
      - Inspection of Troops at Cumberlanding, Pamunkey, Virginia, Circa 1865 (Box V-15)
        Blacksmith's Wagon and Anvil, with Encampment in the Background
        Photographed by Wood & Gibson and published by Gardner
      - Secret Service Department Headquarters, Army of the Potomac, near Antietam, Undated (Box V-15)
      - Studying the Art of War, 1866 (Box V-15)
        Photograph taken in July 1863. Published in Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War
      - Seated photograph of Abraham Lincoln Holding Glasses, Undated (Box V-17, Folder 2)
      - What Do I Want John Henry, 1865-1866 (Box V-17, Folder 3)
        Later silver gelatin copy print.
    - Photographs Attributed to Brady
      - Sherman and his Generals, 1865 (Box V-13)
      - General Winfield Scott and Staff in Washington, 1861 (Box V-13)
      - The 71st New York State Militia and the 71st New York Infantry at the Washington Naval Yard, 1861; 2 photographs (Box V-14)
        New York in Drill Formation (2 copies)
      - Colonel Philip Regis de Trobiand and the 55th New York, 1861; 22.9 x 31.7 cm (Box V-14)
        Daniel Butterfield and the Layfayette Guard
      - Signal Corps Detachment, Elk Mountain, Maryland, 1862 (Box V-15)
      - Ambrose Burnside (and Robert Anderson), Circa 1862 (Box V-16, Folder 4)
        Photographed by D.B. Woodbury.
      - Confederate Prisoners Awaiting Exchange Trains, Belle Plain, Virginia, May 12, 1864 (Box V-16, Folder 4)
      - 5 Photographs Relating to Major General John C. Tidball, 1860s (Box V-16, Folder 5)
        Include comments written by Tidball
    - Photographs by Brady and others
      - Soldier, Full-length Portrait (Box V-4)
        TINTYPE, not Brady
      - Street scene with soldiers, Undated; 35.6 x 25.4 cm (Box V-14)
      - Artillery emplacement, Undated; 35.6 x 25.4 cm (Box V-14)
      - Officers and a dignitary on a porch, Undated; 36.8 x 25.4 cm (Box V-14)
      - A Collection of Three Photographs Depicting the Effects of War, Circa 1861-1865 (Box V-14)
      - Fugitive Slaves Crossing the Rappahannock, 1862 (Box V-16, Folder 4)
        Photograph by Timothy O'Sullivan
      - Alatoona Pass, Georgia - where "Hold the Fort Originated" (Box V-16, Folder 6)
        From the series "The War for the Union Photographic History"
      - Correspondence and photographs from Prisoner of War Camp in Elmira, New York, 1861-1865 (Box V-17, Folder 4)
        Includes stereo views and Cartes des Visite
  - Historian George Sullivan's Mathew Brady Research Archive
    Historian George Sullivan, author of Mathew Brady: His Life and Photographs (1994) and In the Wake of Battle: The Civil War Images of Mathew Brady (2004) was one of the foremost authorities on the life and work of Mathew Brady. This collection, organized in three-ring binders and file folders, comprises correspondence, notes, web printouts, photocopies, photographic prints, and tear sheets, represents Sullivan’s lifetime reference archive.
    - Ephemera and Pamphlets Binder (Box V-20)
    - Civil War Photography Wagons (Box V-21)
    - Images of Mathew Brady (Box V-22)
      Includes original stereo views
    - Brady's Galleries and His Business (Box V-23 and V-24)
    - Brady Daguerreotypes (Box V-25)
    - Brady Biographical Information (Box V-26, Folder 1)
    - Brady's Women (Box V-26, Folder 2)
    - Brady Cases (Box V-26, Folder 3)
    - Brady's Birthplace (Box V-26, Folder 4)
    - 38th Congress (Box V-26, Folder 5)
    - Photographic Portraits (Box V-26, Folder 6)
    - Blue Book Magazine - Cover "Men of America - Mathew Brady", 1951 (Box V-26, Folder 7)
    - Photocopy of The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress with article, "Mathew B. Brady and the Rational of Crime: A Discovery in Daguerreotypes" (Box V-26, Folder 8)
    - Smithsonian Magazine with article about Brady, 1977 (Box V-26, Folder 9)
- Series VI. Lincoln
  - Issues of Harper's Weekly related to Lincoln, his assassination, or Reconstruction., 1863-02-21-1865-04-29 (Box V-10, Folder 11)
    February 21, 1863; March 18 and April 29, 1865.
  - Issues of Harper's Weekly related to Lincoln, 1865-05-06-1866-02-10 (Box V-10, Folder 12)
    May 6 and May 13, 1865; February 10, 1866. Some contain engravings after Brady and Gardener images.
  - Portrait of Abraham Lincoln by Samuel M. Fassett, Circa 1859 (Box VI-1, Folder 1)
    Later print of an 1859 photograph.
  - 2 Portraits of Abraham Lincoln by Alexander Hesler, Circa 1860 (Box VI-1, Folder 2)
    One platinum print and albumen print. Later print of an 1860 photograph
  - Copy of letters regarding the portrait of Lincoln taken by Hesler, Circa 1893 (Box VI-1, Folder 3)
  - Christopher S. German: photograph of Lincoln, marriage license and real estate document, Circa 1861, 1864 (Box VI-1, Folder 4)
  - 3 CDVs of John, James and Harry Ford, undated (Box VI-1, Folder 5)
    The owners and operators of Ford's Theater
  - Ford's Theater employees (Box VI-1, Folder 5)
    5 CDVs and a half of a stereo view
  - 3 CDVs of member of the Lincoln Conspirators Military Trial Commission (Box VI-1, Folder 5)
  - Four Albumen photographs of alleged Lincoln assassination conspirators and Lincoln assassination letter, Circa 1865 (Box VI-1, Folder 6)
    Photographs are of Clement Clay, Jacob Thompson, William W. Cleary and N. Beverly Tucker
  - Alexander Gardner's six studio portraits of the men who conspired to assassinate Abraham Lincoln, 1865-1867 (Box VI-1, Folder 7)
    Photographs of Samuel Bland Arnold, George A. Atzerodt, Michael O'Laughlin, Lewis Paine (nee Powell),
    Edmond Spangler, and John H. Surratt.
  - 1 stereo view of the Lincoln Funeral in New York City (Box VI-1, Folder 8)
  - 1 stereo view of Lincoln's Funeral in New York City (Box VI-1, Folder 5)
  - 2 CDVs of Lincoln's Funeral (Box VI-1, Folder 5)
  - 2 stereo views of Lincoln's Springfield, Illinois home (Box VI-1, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript firsthand account of Lincoln's New York Funeral, 1865 (Box VI-1, Folder 9)
  - Albumen print of Abraham Lincoln by Anthony Berger. Brady and Company Studio. (Box VI-2, Folder 1)
  - Bust portrait of Lincoln, Vignetted by Mathew Brady, 1865 (Box VI-2, Folder 1)
  - Cartes de Visite of Lincoln (Box VI-2, Folder 1)
  - "The Martyr of Freedom" portrait of Lincoln by Charles Magnus, 1865 (Box VI-2, Folder 2)
  - Abraham Lincoln's Funeral Hearse, 1865 (Box VI-2, Folder 2)
    Albumen print of Lincoln's funeral train in Philadelphia.
  - Lincoln's Hearse in Front of the Shop of the Designer, Undertaker Edward Earley", 1865 (Box VI-2, Folder 2)
    Albumen print of Lincoln's funeral hearse in Philadelphia.
  - Printed Lincoln memorial with photograph. (Box VI-2, Folder 3)
  - A collection of thirteen engravings after Lincoln photographs. (Box VI-2, Folder 4)
    Includes engravings after Brady, Gardner, and Berger - folder includes a complete list.
  - Framed photograph of Lincoln's funeral train (Box VI-3)
  - Two Mathew Brady collodion negatives of Justice Samuel Nelson (Box VI-4)
  - Mathew Brady collodion negative of Lincoln Cabinet member Francis E. Spinner (Box VI-4)
  - Mourning pin with black ribbon and image of Lincoln, 1865 (Box VI-5)
  - Campaign Badge with portrait of Lincoln, 1860 (Box VI-5)
  - Cased ambrotype belonging to the William Henry Seward family (Box VI-5)
  - Cased ambrotype of two Abraham Lincoln Wide Awake Marchers (Box VI-5)
  - Framed crayon portrait of Abraham Lincoln, 1864 (Box VI-6)
    Later print by Henszey based on Anthony Berger's Mathew Brady Studios Photograph, February 9, 1864. The signatures of "Henszey Photo." and O.Kohler" appear beneath the image in pencil.
  - William Henry Seward's family CDV album, Undated (Box VI-7)
    Seward was Lincoln's Secretary of State
    The contents of the album have been house separately in the same box.
  - Photograph of Charles A. Leale and family, 1892 (Folder 1)
    Photograph of physician Charles A. Leale and his family at home. Shown are Dr. Leale, his wife Rebecca Medwin Copcutt Leale, and their children Annie, Lilian, Medwin, Marion, and Loyal. The photographer is Pach Bros. Charles A. Leale was the first physician to attend President Lincoln after Lincoln was shot at Ford's Theatre on April 14, 1865.
- Series VII. New York History
  - Views and landmarks of New York City, plus several of Niagara Falls, 1890s; Loeffler, A. (August); Johnston, J.S. (John S.); 43.2 x 35.6 cm; 33 photographs, 16 album pages; Mounted on board with ribbon binding at left edge. (Box VII-2, Folder 1)
    Includes New York Harbor, Statue of Liberty, Central Park, elevated railroads, Niagara Falls and West Point
    On negative: 125,316,534,244,248,251,241,176,105,188,156A,190,191,5,102,234,189,274,99,64A,168,4,146,202,38,154,259,171,14,23
    New York, N.Y.
    Niagara Falls, N.Y.
    Gelatin silver prints
    - William Tweed a.k.a. Boss Tweed of New York Forth Senatorial District, 1867-1871; 21 x 27.3 cm; 1 photograph; Mounted on card with signature (Box VII-2, Folder 2)
    - Men and women walking on the Brooklyn Bridge, 1880s; Loeffler, A. (August); 21.6 x 26.7 cm; 1 photograph; Mounted on board with mat (loose) (Box VII-2, Folder 2)
      Brooklyn Bridge (New York, N.Y.)
    - Brooklyn Bridge and John Roebling, 1860-1869; Wenderoth, Taylor and Brown (Philadelphia); 30.5 x 25.4 cm; 1 photograph; Mounted on board (Box VII-2, Folder 2)
    - A.W. Ayers, Office and Warerooms, Elmira, New York, 1865-1875; Boyd, Walter M.; 35.6 x 43.2 cm; 1 photograph; Mounted on board (Box VII-2, Folder 2)
    - Views and landmarks of New York City, 1870s; 25.4 x 34.3 cm; 1 page, 14 prints; All mounted to single sheet of paper, recto and verso. (Box VII-2, Folder 2)
      New York Stock Exchange
      Grand Central Depot (New York, N.Y.)
    - Views and landmarks of New York City, 1880s; 44.5 x 34.3 cm; 3 pages, 12 prints; Mounted on board, recto and verso. (Box VII-2, Folder 2)
      Central Park, New York, N.Y.
  - 26 Views and Landmarks in New York City, 1870s-1880s; 21.2 x 27.5 cm; 28 photographs (Box VII-3)
    Includes the heavily-wired Western Union building, St. Patrick's Cathedral, Trinity Church, Brooklyn Bridge and the Statue of Liberty
  - Bridge Engineering Binder, 1870-1909; Various; 15 photographs (Box VII-4)
    Includes photographs and negatives of the building of the Brooklyn Bridge as well as photographs, news clippings and correspondence related to bridge engineers such as Charles McDonald, Joseph Wilson, and Washington Roebling.
    Negatives
    Papers (documents)
    Cabinet photographs
  - New York University Portraits, 1862-1865; 10.2 x 6.3 cm; 43 photographs; Mounted on board, recto and verso. Includes pencil inscriptions. Digital prints are reproductions of the albumen prints. (Box VII-5)
    Portraits of students and faculty by C.D. Fredericks and others.
    147
- Series VIII. Edward Curtis: Native Americans and The West, 1925; Curtis, Edward S., 1868-1952; 17 x 14 in (43.2 x 35.6 cm); 15 plates (Box VIII-1-4)
  These gelatin silver glass plate positives were used to make photogravure printing plates to illustrate Curtis's The North American Indian.
  Indians of North America
  Gelatin silver transparencies
  - Taos woman (Box VIII-1, Folder 1)
    Volume XVI, plate 548 of The North American Indian.
    X1636-05 (from negative)
  - Lucero - Santo Domingo (Box VIII-1, Folder 2)
    Volume XVI, plate 557 of The North American Indian.
  - Sia street scene (Box VIII-1, Folder 3)
    Volume XVI, plate 562 of The North American Indian.
  - At the gateway - Acoma (Box VIII-1, Folder 4)
    Volume XVI, plate 569 of The North American Indian.
    X1163-04 (from negative)
  - Laguna watchtower (Box VIII-1, Folder 5)
    Volume XVI, plate 577 of The North American Indian.
  - Paquate watchtower (Box VIII-2, Folder 1)
    Volume XVI, plate 579 of The North American Indian.
  - Moose hunter - Cree (Box VIII-2, Folder 2)
    Volume XVIII, plate 623 of The North American Indian.
  - A medicine headdress - Blackfoot (Box VIII-2, Folder 3)
    Volume XVIII, plate 638 of The North American Indian.
  - Fleshing a hide - Blackfoot (Box VIII-2, Folder 4)
    Volume XVIII, plate 643 of The North American Indian.
  - At the pool, animal dance - Cheyenne (Box VIII-2, Folder 5)
    Volume XIX, plate 663 of The North American Indian.
  - Woista - Cheyenne woman (Box VIII-3, Folder 1)
    Volume XIX, plate 669 of The North American Indian.
  - Old warrior - Arapaho (Box VIII-3, Folder 2)
    Volume XIX, plate 673 of The North American Indian.
  - Esipermi - Comanche (Box VIII-3, Folder 3)
    Volume XIX, plate 682 of The North American Indian.
  - A Comanche (Box VIII-3, Folder 4)
    Volume XIX, plate 686 of The North American Indian.
  - Calf child - Blackfoot, Mounted in custom lightbox by collector for exhibition. (Box VIII-4)
    Volume XVIII, plate 641 of The North American Indian.
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Comte de Paris Civil War photograph album, 8043 Bd. Ms. 1++
Fox Talbot collection of photographs, 8043 Bd. Ms. 2++ v. 1-2
Explorers & Royalty (CDV A), 8043 Bd. Ms. 3++
Varia (CDV B),8043 Bd. Ms. 4++
Scenic (CDV C),8043 Bd. Ms. 5++
Adults (CDV D),8043 Bd. Ms. 6++
Adults (CDV E),8043 Bd. Ms. 6++
Men (CDV F),8043 Bd. Ms. 7++
Women (CDV G),8043 Bd. Ms. 8++
American Notables, Sitters from Brady Studio 1861-1864 (CDV-H), 8043 Bd. Ms. 9++ v. 1
Varia (CDV I),8043 Bd. Ms. 10++
Notables: "Giants of British Art" (CDV 48), 8043 Bd. Ms. 11++
Paris: "Portraits Photographiques Prussiens et Français 1870-71" (CDV 53), 8043 Bd. Ms. 12++
Notables: Portrait photographs of actors, singers, dancers, statesmen, and aristocrats, 8043 Bd. Ms. 13++ v. 1-2
Scientists: "British Association for the Advancement of Science" (CDV 66), 8043 Bd. Ms. 14++
Authors: "Authors" (CDV 16), 8043 Bd. Ms. 15++ v. 1
Authors: "Authors" (plus 20 cabinet cards) (CDV 17), 8043 Bd. Ms. 15++ v. 2
Authors: "Authors" (CDV 18), 8043 Bd. Ms. 15++ v. 3 tiny
Notables: "American and European Notables", 8043 Bd. Ms. 16++
Photographs of Confederate generals (Southern Civil War generals), 8043 Bd. Ms. 17++ v. 1-2
Authors: "Writers, Critics & Journalists" (12 cabinet cards) (CDV 19), 8043 Bd. Ms. 18++
Disraeli: "Disraeli and His Circle: Free trade Convention 1872" (CDV 25), 8043 Bd. Ms. 19++
India: "George Albert Augustus Walker Album" (CDV 30), 8043 Bd. Ms. 20+
Notables: "European Royalty & Notables" (CDV 47.1 & 47.2), 8043 Bd. Ms. 21+